Ambrose Ahawo

Nairobi County, Kenya



ambroseahawo@gmail.com



+254729097858



linkedin.com/in/ambrose-ahawo-8892b1124

Summary

Software engineer with vast experience in the design, development, testing, and maintenance of software applications. Excellent skills in Python, Django, Nodejs, AWS, MySQL, React, etc.

I have experience in supporting and fixing bugs in existing projects. correcting and optimizing other developers' code. My working process includes a clear understanding of business details and implementing them into code.

I believe in teamwork, collaboration, and a ready for a challenging new role where skills, knowledge, and previous experience can be applied and further professional development achieved.

Experience

System Architect

Pesaflow

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Digitizing manual government services

Collaborating with other developers in visualizing automated systems.

Collaborating with government agencies and ministries towards transforming manual services to digital services

Interacted with elixir and liquid programming

Acted as a team lead in implementing digital government services

υρ Software Developer

Upwork

May 2020 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Developing highly-scalable backend systems on python-Django framework

Data extraction, web scraping with scrapy, beautifulsoup and selenium

Gaining data insights through data mining and analysis

Back-end Development (Python-Django, Nodejs)

Data extraction (Python, scrapy, BeautifulSoup, webcrawling, pandas), Data Mining, Data Analysis. front-end development (JavaScript, reactjs, vuejs)



Junior Software Developer

Netbot Solutions Limited

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022 (2 months)

Developed and implemented backend applications on django-rest framework

Implemented rest apis on reactjs frontend

Implemented new features based on business requirements

Collaborated with a team of developers and product managers in implementing eCommerce systems

Information Technology Intern

Siaya Institute of Technology

Jun 2021 - Oct 2021 (5 months)

Mastered cable crimping and wall mounting.

Worked on fixing damaged ethernet cables for already existing installations.

Perfected my skills in team-work.

Network monitoring.

Computer hardware diagnosis.

SOFTWARE SUPPORT SPECIAIST

MOSCOM CYBERCAFE

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 (5 months)

Education

Moi University, KENYA

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics

2016 - 2021

My career is an IT based involving engineering and management of computer based Information systems. I had an opportunity to learn various key technology concepts such as;-

Data Structures and Algorithms

Computer Programming

Database Management

Artificial Intelligence

e.t.c

Skills

IT Services • Network Administration • PostgreSQL • JavaScript Libraries • System Architecture • Software Architecture • Web Development • Software Development • Technical Support • Programming